<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on SLU Data Science Seminar</title>
    <link>/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on SLU Data Science Seminar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag: Adding Python to `R` Workflows</title>
      <link>/news/pythonr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/pythonr/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for another installment of our occasional brownbag series. Srikanth Mudigonda, Ph.D., the Director of the M.S. in Applied Analytics, will be giving a short overview of how to use Python via RStudio (and why you might want to!). The upcoming release of RStudio v1.2 integrates fully into Python, and includes the ability to mix Python and R code in R markdown documents.
This will be the DSS&amp;rsquo;s second Python related lesson and is being used to help us develop a plan for offering Python content moving forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag: Iteration in `R` using `purrr`</title>
      <link>/news/purrr19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/purrr19/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for another installment of our occasional brownbag series. Srikanth Mudigonda, Ph.D., the Director of the M.S. in Applied Analytics, will be giving a short overview of techniques for iterating in R using the most modern, tidyverse-centric approach - purrr.
The purrr package offers a powerful interface for repeating the same task over observations, variables, or over pieces of information stored in vectors or lists. It can be used to read in a large number of spreadsheets and collapse them automatically into a single sheet, search strings for a list of different words, and iterate over observations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag: Making Science More Open</title>
      <link>/news/opensci19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/opensci19/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for another installment of our occasional brownbag series. The DSS and the Department of Psychology&amp;rsquo;s E-tea group are jointly sponsoring this event, which will include an overview of open science techniques and a discussion of how to implement them in your work. We&amp;rsquo;ll be talking about how to make code and data shareable and citable, using the Open Science Framework, and depositing pre-prints in repositories.
Where: Location TBD</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2019 Data Science Meetup</title>
      <link>/news/meetup19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Feb 2019 00:10:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/meetup19/</guid>
      <description>Overview This past October, we brought the open science community at SLU together for a gathering to discuss where we&amp;rsquo;re at and where we could be. On March 29th, we&amp;rsquo;re taking a next step towards a broader, more inclusive data science and open community here at SLU.
One thing that we&amp;rsquo;ve learned is many computational researchers describe feeling like &amp;ldquo;islands of one&amp;rdquo;. The spring data science meetup will therefore feature a faculty lighting talk session for faculty and staff researchers engaged in data science and computational work (lunch provided) followed by a coffee break.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSS Seminar 07: Data Wrangling in R</title>
      <link>/news/dss07/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/dss07/</guid>
      <description>The four seminar sessions for the Spring 2019 seminar will cover ways to use R for data cleaning and wrangling. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover techniques for dealing with messy variable names, removing variables and adding new ones, subsetting observations, and summarizing grouped data using the R packages dplyr and janitor. We’ll discuss:
 Lesson 1 - January 23rd - Working with Existing Variables Lesson 2 - February 6th - Creating New Variables Lesson 3 - February 20th - Managing Observations Lesson 4 - March 6th - Grouping and Summarizing Data  No prior experience with R is necessary - in fact, these seminars are tailored to learners with no or little experience in R!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag: Using Python for Automating Routine Tasks</title>
      <link>/news/pythonroutine/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/pythonroutine/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for another installment of our occasional brownbag series. Srikanth Mudigonda, Ph.D., the Director of the M.S. in Applied Analytics, will be giving a short overview of techniques for automating routine data analysis and research tasks using Python. This will be the DSS&amp;rsquo;s first Python related lesson and is being used to help us develop a plan for offering Python content moving forward. If you are interested in using Python for data science, please join us in helping build this community at SLU!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag: Power Analysis Primer in R</title>
      <link>/news/poweranalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/poweranalysis/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for another installment of our occasional brownbag series. Matthew Schuelke, Ph.D. a statistician in the Office of the Vice President of Research who is also a faculty member at SLUCOR, will be giving a short overview of techniques for producing power analyses using R. These are important study design skills that ensure you are sampling or enrolling enough participants to address the questions you want to answer in your study.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSS Seminar 06: Reproducible Research in R</title>
      <link>/news/dss06/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/dss06/</guid>
      <description>The four sessions for the Fall 2018 seminar will cover ways to use R for conducting reproducible research. We’ll discuss:
 Lesson 1 - September 5th - Introduction to R and RStudio Lesson 2 - September 19th - Reading and Writing Data with readr, readxl, and haven Lesson 3 - October 3rd - Notebooks and RMarkdown Lesson 4 - October 17th - Using knitr  If you are new to R, you are strongly encouraged to commit to all four seminars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2018 Open Science Meetup</title>
      <link>/news/meetup18/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/meetup18/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for a new event we are sponsoring - the first of what we hope will become an annual series of meetups for the open science and open source community on campus. We are bringing together open science practioners and users of open source software from around the SLU community to help faculty, research scientists, staff, and graduate students network. Our secondary goal for this event is to set an agenda for open science at SLU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Atlas Week 2018</title>
      <link>/news/atlas18/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/atlas18/</guid>
      <description>Accessible Data Analysis: Using St. Louis Data to Explore Global Issues In this workshop, we&amp;rsquo;ll use publicly available data about St. Louis to introduce open source data analysis software (R) that can be used to explore and respond to questions that are of concern to communities worldwide. We’ll use two local datasets to introduce participants to the art of data analysis: information on income, and asthma rates, for St. Louis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownbag: Meta-Analysis in R</title>
      <link>/news/metaanalysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/metaanalysis/</guid>
      <description>Please join us for another installment of our occasional brownbag series. Assistant Professor Cort Rudolph, from the Department of Psychology, will be giving a short overview of techniques for producing meta-analyses using R. Meta-analysis is a statistical technique for evaluating the effects found in multiple scientific studies. No experience with meta-analysis is required. While some basic familiarity with R is helpful, it is also not required.
Where: 3600 Morrissey Hall</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSS Seminar 05: Functions &amp; Packages in R</title>
      <link>/news/dss05/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/dss05/</guid>
      <description>The four sessions for the Spring 2018 seminar will cover ways to use R for managing research projects. We’ll discuss how to write functions that automate repetitive tasks, how to include those functions in your own package, and how to track your package development work using Git and GitHub. No prior experience with R, package development, Git, or GitHub is necessary!
Where: 3600 Morrissey Hall
When: Wednesdays (Jan. 24, Feb. 7, Feb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DSS Seminar 04: Mapping Data in R</title>
      <link>/news/dss04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/dss04/</guid>
      <description>Our Fall, 2017 seminar series will be a four-part introduction to working with spatial data in R. We&amp;rsquo;ll cover the basics of spatial data structures, merging data frames, and using ggplot2 to create maps. No experience with R, GIS work, or mapping is required! Please note that we ask that participants commit to all four seminar dates.
Where: 3600 Morrissey Hall
When: Wednesdays (Sept. 20, Oct. 4, Oct. 18, &amp;amp; Nov.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protecting Your Data</title>
      <link>/news/protectdata/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/protectdata/</guid>
      <description>On September 6th, we will be hosting a short one-hour seminar focused on some general strategies for protecting your research data against hard drive failure, structure fires, natural disasters, and other calamities. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever worried about what would happen to your work if this happened at your home or in your office but aren&amp;rsquo;t sure how to back your data up effectively, this seminar is for you! We&amp;rsquo;ll introduce some basic strategies and have plenty of time for Q &amp;amp; A.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>